A billion light years from Earth, the human race is fighting for survival.
Battlestar Galactica is a science fiction, adventure
film directed by Richard A. Colla.
A compilation of Battlestar Galactica episodes 1 and 5, with alternate footage.
After the destruction of the Twelve Colonies of Mankind, the last major fighter carrier leads a
makeshift fugitive fleet in a desperate search for the legendary planet Earth.
Capt. Apollo, played by Richard Hatch.
Lt. Starbuck, played by Dirk Benedict.
Cmdr. Adama, played by Lorne Greene.
Lt. Boomer, played by Herbert Jefferson Jr..
Lt. Athena, played by Maren Jensen.
Cassiopeia, played by Laurette Spang.
"Saga of a Star World" (aka “Battlestar Galactica”) is the pilot for the American science
fiction television series Battlestar Galactica which was produced in 1978 by Glen A.
A re-edit of the episode was released theatrically as Battlestar Galactica in Canada before the
television series aired in the United States, in order to help recoup its high production costs.
Later, the standalone film edit was also released in
the United States and internationally.
The film explores themes of space marine, space
battle, space mission, space, compilation.
The tone is thought_provoking.